本视频由Brilliant赞助
This video is supported by Brilliant.
在过去一百年间 航空旅行以其越来越低的票价和越来越高的安全性
Over the last 100 years, air travel has become accessible to almost everyone
已经逐渐深入寻常百姓家
through the increase in airline safety and the reduction in ticket prices.
但飞机再怎么进化
But as current airplanes continue to evolve,
物理法则也不会让它再快到哪里去
the limitations of physics have stopped us from going faster and further.
但如果有一种能极大缩短飞行时间的旅行方法呢？
But what if there was a new method to Earth travel that would cut flight times massively?
航天公司维珍银河和太空叉都在致力于让此事变成现实
Space companies Virgin Galactic and SpaceX are trying to make this a reality
他们想用各自的火箭进行地球上的快速点对点旅行
by using their rocket powered vehicles for super fast travel here on Earth.
太空叉计划使用他们原本设计用于前往火星的Starship火箭来进行地球旅行
SpaceX plans to use their Starship rocket,
primarily designed for Mars, to transport passengers to major cities on Earth.
这些火箭将在地球大气层外飞行
Since these flights would go above the Earth's atmosphere,
所以火箭的速度会远高于民航客机
it would allow the rocket to reach much higher speeds than an airliner.
这意味着地球上任意两点的旅行时间都将小于一小时
This means that flights to anywhere on Earth could be done in less than an hour.
飞行应该不会很平稳 因为乘客在起飞着陆的时候回承受几个G的加速度
The ride itself would not be smooth, as passengers would experience g-forces during launch and landing
有点像坐过山车
similar to riding a rollercoaster.
然而 旅行中绝大多数时间都是在太空滑行
However, for the majority of the ride, the rocket would be coasting through space
乘客会感受到失重
and passengers would experience zero-gravity.
这让火箭上的厕所和餐车之类常用设施的设计更加复杂
This makes the design of inflight amenities like bathrooms and food carts much more complex.
然而 由于飞行时间非常短 这些设施的使用需求应该也不会太高
However, since the flight times would be so short, the need for such amenities might not be so high.
维珍银河也在探寻地球点对点太空旅行的潜力
Virgin Galactic is also exploring the potential of Earth to Earth spaceship travel -
但他们的方法完全不同
but their method is completely different.
他们用的不是火箭 而是由火箭驱动的太空飞机
Instead of a rocket, Virgin is developing a rocket powered space-plane
先由飞机带到高空 然后在空中进行发射
which can be carried up to high altitudes and launched in mid-air.
两种方法理论上都能极大缩短飞行时间
Both methods could theoretically reduce flight times by an enormous margin -
但在两家公司可以发射乘客到太空之前
but before either of these companies can launch passengers around the globe,
他们要解决一大堆问题
they have to overcome a lot of challenges.
太空叉为了解决火箭发射时发生的巨大噪音
In order for SpaceX to get around the enormous amount of sound produced by their rocket,
发射需要远离城市 很可能是在海中
launches would need to take place far away from cities, perhaps out in the ocean.
因此需要额外的将乘客运输到发射场的步骤
All of this will require more transportation for passengers getting to and from the launch site.
维珍银河可能这方面的问题比较小
Virgin would likely have less trouble getting regulatory approval
因为他们的飞机起飞和着陆和普通民航飞机起降没什么区别
since their take off and landing procedure is much more similar to traditional air travel
而且可以使用目前已有的机场设施
and could use the pre-existing infrastructure of airports.
维珍银河计划在全球建立一套太空运输网络
Virgin has plans to build a network of spaceports around the world
包括当前在英国南部正在开发的一块场地
including one in the south of England which is currently under development.
这块额外的太空港可以让维珍银河进行跨大西洋飞行测试
This additional spaceport would allow Virgin to perform transatlantic test flights
测试中他们将往返他们在新墨西哥州已有的太空港
to and from their existing spaceport in New Mexico.
但即使两家公司都获取了营业执照
But even if both companies get passed the regulatory approval,
他们在票价上还要面临巨大挑战
they still face massive challenges in the form of ticket prices.
火箭需要像民航客机那样可重复使用才能有与其接近的票价
A rocket needs to be as reusable as an airliner in order to achieve similar ticket prices.
虽然维珍银河的方案更接近目前的民航旅行
Although Virgin's plan seems more familiar to current air travel,
但想要让票价降到合适的范围内还有很长的路要走
it will have a harder time achieving a reasonable ticket price.
他们的飞机太小 一次只能承载六名旅客和两名飞行员
With such a small vehicle, only 6 passengers and 2 pilots can fly at a time,
使得单座价格很高
making the cost per ticket much higher.
尽管现在贵的离谱 但还有700多个有意愿的乘客在排队
Despite the price, almost 700 eager passengers are already on the waiting list
想要搭乘他们的二号船VSS Unity进行亚轨道飞行
for a suborbital flight aboard VSS Unity.
但在这些载客旅行成为现实之前
But before these passenger flights can become a reality,
两家公司还要解决太空飞行的一个最大挑战：安全
both companies will need to overcome one of spaceflight's greatest challenges, safety.
在2017年 民航平均每运输六千万人只有一次死亡
In 2017, the aviation industry had just 1 death for every 60 million passengers.
而目前为止 在航天界 这个数字是每32个宇航员死亡一人
So far, the spaceflight industry has a rate of 1 death for every 32 astronauts,
这里18这个数字是执行实际任务中的数据：
联盟1号 降落伞故障 1人死亡
联盟11号 飞船失压 3人死亡
挑战者号与哥伦比亚号空难 共14人死亡
总共570人进入太空 其中有18人遇难
since out of the 570 people that have been into space, 18 have died.
整个商业航天界想要达到安全的标准还有很长的路要走
Meeting the safety standards remains a challenge across all commercial spaceflight,
相关视频：av21807258
尤其在2014年维珍银河的VSS企业号飞机悲剧性的坠毁事故之后
especially after the tragic crash of Virgin's VSS Enterprise in 2014.
另外 虽然乘客在这样的旅行中可以节省很多时间
Although passenger travel could save us a huge amount of time,
但大家经常忽视的一个生理上的问题
one thing that is often overlooked is the physiological impacts it could have.
以如此快的速度进行环球旅行可能会对身体带来一些奇怪影响
Travelling around the world this fast could have weird effects on our bodies
因为我们日常黑白轮转的生物钟可能会受到影响
since we would be deprived of the usual day/night cycle.
乘客可能看着日出醒来
Passengers could wake up to watch the sunrise,
然后横穿半个地球 在不到一个小时的时间里看到太阳落山
then travel across the world to watch the sunset in less than an hour.
如此快的倒时差可能会带来比常规民航旅行更严重的生理反应
This rapid change in time zones would create a much more intense feeling of jet lag
than we are used to from regular airline travel.
太空叉和维珍银河能否将太空旅行变为现实目前还是个未知数
Whether SpaceX or Virgin Galactic can turn the dream of Earth to Earth rocket travel into a reality remains unknown.
但商业航天正朝着实现这种革命性的旅行方式而大步前进
However, commercial space programs are making huge strides
towards achieving this revolutionary method of transportation
而我们的前途也是一片光明 令人兴奋！
in order to make our future much more exciting!
为了实现这一雄心勃勃的目标
In order to achieve this ambitious goal,
两家公司都需要雇佣像你一样对太空感兴趣的 充满激情的人
both of these companies will need to hire people like you that are interested and passionate about all things space.
然后就是猝不及防的恰饭 就不翻了
Even if you don't have a formal science education, you can start your learning adventure using Brilliant.
Brilliant is a website that makes learning accessible and fun.
Their problem solving approach allows you to think critically about complex topics and truly understand them.
It's about seeing concepts visually and interacting with them, and then answering questions that get you to think.
Their courses are laid out like a story, and broken down into pieces so that you can tackle them one step at a time.
There's no tests and no grades — just pick a course based on what you're interested in, and get started.
Choose the course that's right for you and learn at your own pace —
whether you want to brush up on the basics of algebra, learn programming, or learn about cutting-edge topics like Neural Networks.
To try it out yourself and support the channel, visit brilliant.org/primalspace.
The first 200 people to sign up will get 20% off the yearly subscription.
Thank you very much for watching and I'll see you in the next video.